<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Recording on Ardour tutorial</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/recording/</link><description>Recent content in Recording on Ardour tutorial</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/recording/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Recording audio</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/recording/recording-audio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/recording/recording-audio/</guid><description>&lt;p>Besides importing existing audio files, another way to create regions in your
Ardour session is to &lt;em>record&lt;/em> new audio.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The source of this audio could be the line or microphone inputs of your audio
interface, or it could even be sound originating from other applications on
your computer which have been connected to Ardour via JACK. Please see the
&lt;a href="../understanding-routing/">section on routing&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This section will show you how to record audio from an external source (for
example, a microphone) onto a track in Ardour.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Recording MIDI</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/recording/recording-midi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/recording/recording-midi/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are several ways to get MIDI into a MIDI track in Ardour apart from
importing an existing MIDI file. Let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at them one by one.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="real-time-recording">Real-time recording&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Perhaps the most obvious option to record MIDI into Ardour is connecting a
MIDI keyboard to your audio interface or your computer directly and recording
whatever you play. It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty straightforward process:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select an existing MIDI track to record to or create a new one&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Performing on time</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/recording/performing-on-time/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/recording/performing-on-time/</guid><description>&lt;p>Normally, to record an instrument or a vocal part live, you place the playhead
to some position, arm a track for recording, toggle the overall record mode
and then roll the transport whenever you are ready. Recording will start at
the playhead position, and you will listen the audible part of the session
material that also starts at that point. There are two important
considerations here.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="using-a-metronome">Using a metronome&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You might not yet have the beats part of the material to guide you when you
are recording. So if performing to a metronome to pace yourself is something
you are comfortable with, you can enable the metronome on the transport
toolbar (or press the &lt;strong>`&lt;/strong> shortcut).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Understanding routing</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/recording/understanding-routing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/recording/understanding-routing/</guid><description>&lt;p>Routing an audio signal is sending it from somewhere to somewhere else.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition to getting audio signals to and from Ardour, routing plays an
important part inside Ardour itself. Examples of using routing inside Ardour
include routing audio from tracks to the &lt;em>Master&lt;/em> bus or to other busses,
creating &amp;lsquo;sends&amp;rsquo;, routing the outputs from busses to the &lt;em>Master&lt;/em> bus, etc. (see
chapter on &lt;strong>Creating a Track&lt;/strong> for an explanation of tracks and busses). All
routing, both internal and external to Ardour, is handled by JACK.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Routing between applications</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/recording/routing-between-applications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/recording/routing-between-applications/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sometimes you may need to record the audio output of another program into
Ardour, e.g. the sound of a YouTube video playing in Firefox, or the output of
SuperCollider or PureData. This chapter shows how to accomplish that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The examples on this page were created on a computer running Ubuntu Linux.
Beware that things may work differently if you are on another OS (in particular
if you are using a Mac). The general principles are always the same, though.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>