<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Editing sessions on Ardour tutorial</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/editing-sessions/</link><description>Recent content in Editing sessions on Ardour tutorial</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/editing-sessions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Non-destructive editing</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/editing-sessions/non-destructive-editing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/editing-sessions/non-destructive-editing/</guid><description>In one of the previous chapters we already discussed that Ardour operates on sessions that encompass all material you have: audio clips, MIDI clips, all effects applied to tracks and busses etc. Before we get to actual editing, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about basics of non-destructive editing, how it&amp;rsquo;s implemented in Ardour, and why it should give you peace of mind when you do some heavy editing.
What does non-destructive editing actually mean?</description></item><item><title>Arranging tracks</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/editing-sessions/arranging-tracks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/editing-sessions/arranging-tracks/</guid><description>In the following chapters we will use Ardour to create a short rhythmic passage using several drumkit samples.
We will continue working on this passage in later tutorials, such as Working with Regions and Creating Looped Sections. We assume that you have read the chapters in the Getting Started section already, and are familiar with Importing Audio, Tracks, and the Timeline.
Importing Samples The first step is to add some sounds, which is discussed at length in the Importing Audio chapter.</description></item><item><title>Setting up the meter</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/editing-sessions/setting-up-the-meter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/editing-sessions/setting-up-the-meter/</guid><description>The meter, or time signature, determines the musical speed of the passage we are composing and is measured in beats per bars.
If we are composing something rhythmic, it will also determine the lengths of the sound samples we use to some extent. So it is important to be able to set up the meter before we continue.
To see the meter-related timelines for the session, you can right-click anywhere in the &amp;ldquo;header&amp;rdquo; of the rulers and check the following options: Meter, Bars &amp;amp; Beats, and Tempo.</description></item><item><title>Using ranges</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/editing-sessions/using-ranges/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/editing-sessions/using-ranges/</guid><description>A range is a selection of the timeline that can include one or more tracks. It has many uses like selecting a portion of audio/MIDI data to cut it.
Creating ranges There are two common ways to create a range:
You can do it with the Grab tool (G shortcut) when the Smart mode is enabled. In that case you need to position the mouse pointer around the middle of a track vertically to start selecting data rather than picking and moving a region.</description></item><item><title>Working with regions</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/editing-sessions/working-with-regions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/editing-sessions/working-with-regions/</guid><description>Sections of audio are called Regions in Ardour.
To compose the short rhythmic passage we&amp;rsquo;ve been working on, we will need to know how to Select, Move, Split and Trim these Regions, as well as how to Fade In or Fade Out their volume and create Crossfades between them. Some of these options may need to happen at specific Edit Points in the composition, or according to the musical Meter we can define with the Timeline and the Grid as well.</description></item><item><title>Further region operations</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/editing-sessions/further-region-operations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/editing-sessions/further-region-operations/</guid><description>In this section you will learn a few more things you can do with Regions.
Right-clicking a selected Region reveals a context menu. The first item in the menu (labeled with the Region&amp;rsquo;s name) contains a large sub-menu. All of these operations are also available from Ardour&amp;rsquo;s main Region menu.
This section describes a few of the most commonly used operations accessible from these menus.
Play: play back from the beginning to the end of that Region (shortcut &amp;ldquo;H&amp;rdquo;).</description></item><item><title>Changing edit modes</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/editing-sessions/changing-edit-modes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/editing-sessions/changing-edit-modes/</guid><description>We have already learned a bit about the Grab Mode (select/move objects) and Range Mode. In this chapter we will get an overview of all the Edit Modes and Cursor Modes available on that part of the Editor Window.
Edit Modes and Cursor Modes These controls define the behavior of the main canvas and the different functions of the cursor.
The drop-down Edit Mode menu contains three options. Slide Edit is the standard mode, and the one we will be using in this tutorial.</description></item><item><title>Creating looped sections</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/editing-sessions/creating-looped-sections/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/editing-sessions/creating-looped-sections/</guid><description>You can easily repeat sections of audio in your Ardour session.
Here, we take the short rhythmic passage we created in Working with Regions and duplicate it to make a loop.
Before duplicating the passage, it is a good idea to combine individual regions in the same track into a single one: it is easier to move them around this way, and it prevents you from accidentally moving a single hihat out of place, for example.</description></item><item><title>Stretching &amp; shrinking regions</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/editing-sessions/stretching-shrinking-regions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/editing-sessions/stretching-shrinking-regions/</guid><description>Regions can be stretched or shrunk in length without changing their Pitch by using the Stretch/Shrink Regions tool (shortcut &amp;ldquo;T&amp;rdquo;, for &amp;ldquo;Time stretch&amp;rdquo;).
A small adjustment to the length of a Region may not cause noticeable sound Artifacts. However, the more extreme the change in length, the more obvious the effect of processing on the sound.
To use Stretch/Shrink Regions, place your cursor on top of the region, and then Click-drag left or right.</description></item></channel></rss>