<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Appendices on Ardour tutorial</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/appendices/</link><description>Recent content in Appendices on Ardour tutorial</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/appendices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Further help</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/appendices/further-help/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/appendices/further-help/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are a couple of resources on the Internet to help you learn Ardour and
fix some of the problems that you might have along the way.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ardour-manual">Ardour Manual&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The official &lt;a href="http://manual.ardour.org/">Ardour Manual&lt;/a> is the main reference to Ardour. It is a work in progress, meaning you will not find every single feature explained there (yet). But it is already an amazing resource:&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="getting-help-via-chat">Getting Help via Chat&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A good way to get support when learning Ardour and working with it is using the
&lt;strong>Chat&lt;/strong> function. Ardour has a built-in &amp;ldquo;Chat&amp;rdquo; option, found in the main menu
under &lt;code>Help &amp;gt; Chat&lt;/code> to connect (via your web browser) to the Ardour
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IRC">IRC&lt;/a> channel at libera.chat.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Glossary</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/appendices/glossary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/appendices/glossary/</guid><description>&lt;p>This glossary offers brief definitions for many of the terms used throughout the Ardour 8 FLOSS Tutorial.&lt;/p>
&lt;dl>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Aggregate Device&lt;/strong> (macOS)&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>An Aggregate Device is one virtual soundcard made of two or more
physical soundcards. PowerBooks and MacBooks made in 2007 or later will
need this set up in order for &lt;em>JACK&lt;/em> to have both input and output
channels. This is set up in the &lt;em>Audio MIDI Setup&lt;/em> application.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>AIFF&lt;/strong>&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>A sound file format developed by Apple and commonly used for lossless
and uncompressed audio. AIFF files are compatible with Windows,
Macintosh and Linux operating systems.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>ALSA&lt;/strong> (Linux)&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>Advanced Linux Sound Architecture. ALSA provides audio and MIDI
functionality to the Linux operating system.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Amplitude&lt;/strong> (mixing)&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>The strength of an audio signal. The scale of amplitude is
&lt;em>*logarithmic&lt;/em>, since it expresses the physical ratio of power between
one sound and another. Levels in digital audio systems are usually
represented as the number of Decibels below the clipping point of 0 dB.
See also &lt;em>loudness&lt;/em>.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Arm&lt;/strong> (Track to record/Ardour to record)&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>Action that makes Ardour ready to start recording. Before recording in
Ardour, one or more tracks need to be armed first, and then Ardour needs
to be armed itself.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Artifacts&lt;/strong> (sound)&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>Perceivable distortion or decrease in sound quality generated as a
by-product of certain signal processing operations. Artefacts are
usually seen as undesirable or unexpected results of an otherwise
intentional sound transformation.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Attenuation&lt;/strong>&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>Reducing the &lt;strong>level&lt;/strong> of an audio signal, usually measured using a
&lt;em>logarithmic&lt;/em> scale. See also &lt;em>gain&lt;/em>.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Audio MIDI Setup&lt;/strong> (macOS)&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>The Audio MIDI Setup utility is a program that comes with the macOS
operating system for adjusting the computer&amp;rsquo;s audio input and output
configuration settings and managing MIDI devices.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Audio Unit Plugins&lt;/strong>&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>Audio Unit (AU) is a plugin architecture in macOS computers. It may
be thought of as Apple&amp;rsquo;s equivalent to the popular VST plugin format by
Steinberg. MacOS comes with a collection of AU plug-ins such as EQ
filters, dynamic processors, delay, reverb, time stretch, among others.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Audition&lt;/strong>&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>The auditioner is a hidden mixer strip which auditioned regions are
played back through. Auditioning a region will play only that region,
without processing sends or plugins.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Automation&lt;/strong>&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>Automation is the automatic adjustment of various parameters such as
gain, panning or plugin settings. Changes can be made once and then will
be repeated every time the mix is replayed. Automation in Ardour is
controlled by automation lines linked to each Track or Bus.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Auxiliary Controls&lt;/strong>&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>Buttons on the top right side of the controls found in the Editor
Window: Punch In/Out, Auto Play, Auto Return, Auto Input, Click, Solo,
and Audition.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Amplitude&lt;/strong>&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>The level or magnitude of a signal. Audio signals with a higher
amplitude usually sound louder.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Bands&lt;/strong> (equalization)&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>The particular frequency regions to be boosted or attenuated in the
process of &lt;em>Equalization&lt;/em>.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Bars&lt;/strong> (music)&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>Same as &amp;lsquo;measure&amp;rsquo;, a bar is a metrical unit. In Western notation, it is
the space comprised between two vertical lines drawn through the staff.
The specific duration of a bar depends of its &lt;em>time signature&lt;/em> and the
current &lt;em>tempo&lt;/em> of the music.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Bass&lt;/strong> (Frequencies)&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>A generic way of referring to the lower frequencies of the &lt;em>spectrum&lt;/em>
of a sound.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Beat&lt;/strong>&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>The basic pulse underlying a piece of music.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Beats per Minute&lt;/strong>&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>Beats per minute (BPM) is a measure of tempo in music. A rate of 60
beats per minute means that one beat will occur every second; 120 bpm
equals two beats per second, and so on. BPM indications usually appear
at the beginning of a traditional musical score as a metronome mark (for
example, &amp;ldquo;quarter note equals 60&amp;rdquo;, meaning one quarter note per second).&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Bit&lt;/strong>&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>A bit (&lt;strong>bi&lt;/strong>nary dig&lt;strong>it&lt;/strong>) is a single number with a value of either 0
or 1.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Bit Depth&lt;/strong>&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>Refers to the number of bits used to write a &lt;em>sample&lt;/em>. In the CD
standard, each sample of audio is represented by a 16-bit number. This
gives 2^16 (two to the power of sixteen = 65,536) possible values that
a sample can have. A higher bit depth means a greater possible &lt;em>dynamic
range&lt;/em>. Studio recordings are usually first made recorded with a bit
depth of 24 (or even 32) to preserve as much detail before transfer to
CD. DVDs are made at 24 bit, while video games from the 1980s remain
famous for their distinctively rough &amp;ldquo;8 bit sound&amp;rdquo;. Bit depth is also
referred to as &lt;strong>word length&lt;/strong>.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Buffer Size&lt;/strong> (JACK)&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>The buffer is a section of memory specifically allotted to temporary
signal data. Small buffer sizes allow a lower latency and so are needed
when using audio applications that require real-time interaction. The
drawback is that CPU consumption for the system is higher with smaller
buffer sizes. Larger buffers (like 512 or 1024) can be used when there
is no such requirement.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Built-in Input and Output&lt;/strong>&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>These are the default interfaces for getting sound in and out of your
computer if you don&amp;rsquo;t have an external sound card. In a laptop, they are
the common input (mic) and output (headphone) connections.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Bus&lt;/strong>&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>A bus is similar to a track except that it does not contain its
own regions. You cannot record directly into a bus or drag regions into
it. The &lt;em>Mixer&lt;/em> strip vertically represents the signal flow of a bus,
whereas the Main Canvas horizontally displays time-based information for
each bus (such as automation lines).&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>BWF&lt;/strong>&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>Broadcast Wave Format (BWF) is an extension of the popular Microsoft
WAVE audio format and is the recording format of most file-based
non-linear digital recorders used for motion picture and television
production. This file format allows the inclusion of metadata to
facilitate the seamless exchange of sound data between different
computer platforms and applications.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>CAF&lt;/strong>&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>CAF (Core Audio Format) is a file format for storing audio, developed by
Apple. It is compatible with macOS 10.4 and higher. The Core Audio
Format is designed to overcome limitations of older digital audio
formats, including AIFF and WAV. Just like the QuickTime .mov file
format, a .caf file format can contain many different audio formats,
metadata tracks, and much more data.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Center Frequency&lt;/strong>&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>In some EQ plugins, the user has the possibility of choosing the center
frequency for each of the frequency bands. The center frequency of a
Band will be the one most sharply attenuated or reinforced by the
equalizer for that specific band. Frequencies surrounding the center
frequency will be less affected.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Click&lt;/strong> (Mouse)&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>In this manual, it specifically means to click on the left button of
your mouse. Whenever the right button is required, the action is
referred to as &amp;ldquo;right-click&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Clipping&lt;/strong>&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>Clipping occurs when a signal is too high in level to be reproduced. Any
samples too high in level will simply be truncated, resulting in
&lt;em>distortion&lt;/em>, loss of audio detail, and artefact &lt;em>frequencies&lt;/em> which
were not present in the original sound.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Clipping Point&lt;/strong>&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>The clipping point of a digital system is referred to as 0 dB, and
the level of any sound is measured in how far below the clipping point
it is (-10 dB, -24 dB, etc).&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Clocks&lt;/strong>&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>The two big numerical displays near the top of the &lt;em>Editor&lt;/em> window. They can
display the time in a number of formats: &lt;em>Timecode&lt;/em>, &lt;em>Bars:Beats&lt;/em>,
&lt;em>Minutes:Seconds&lt;/em>, and &lt;em>Samples&lt;/em>.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Compile&lt;/strong>&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>FLOSS applications are distributed as source code, which is human-readable but
cannot be run as an actual application. To turn this source code into a running
application, it must first be Compiled. When you download a disk image for macOS
or a software package from your distribution (such as Ubuntu, Debian or Fedora),
it has been compiled for you already. However, if you wish to add features (such
as support for &lt;em>VST Plugins&lt;/em>) which your distribution does not provide, then
you must compile the application from source code yourself.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Compression&lt;/strong>(DSP)&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>Essentially, compression makes the quiet parts of a signal louder
without changing the level of
the louder parts. This entails a reduction of the actual dynamic range:
a compressed sound is less dynamic (has a smaller range of levels)&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Compression&lt;/strong> (data)&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>Like any other data, audio data can be compressed so that it uses less
hard disk space. Compression such as FLAC, ALAC, or MLP reduce the size
of audio files compared to WAV or AIFF without changing the data, which
is referred to as lossless compression. Audio can be compressed to a
still smaller size by using lossy compression such as MP3, Ogg Vorbis or
AAC but this is achieved by removing data which can have an audible
effect.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Connections Manager&lt;/strong>(JACK)&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>The window in Jack that allows to manage all connections between audio
inputs and outputs.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>CoreAudio&lt;/strong>(macOS)&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>CoreAudio provides audio functionality to the macOS operating system.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Cursor Modes&lt;/strong>&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>These are the six buttons just below the Transport commands in the
Editor Window. The six different functions that the mouse pointer can
have in Ardour are: Select/Move Objects, Select/Move Ranges, Select Zoom
Range, Draw Gain Automation, Stretch/Shrink Regions, Listen to Specific
Regions.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Decibels&lt;/strong>&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>Decibel is a logarithmic scale used to measure many quantities,
including the &lt;em>gain&lt;/em>, &lt;em>level&lt;/em> or &lt;em>loudness&lt;/em> of a signal. Decibel
is usually abbreviated to dB and in digital audio usually denotes how
far under 0 dBFS (the &lt;em>clipping&lt;/em> point of a system) a signal is.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Delay&lt;/strong> (effect)&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>The amount of time between one event and another. As an audio effect, a delay
takes an incoming sound signal and delays it for a certain length of time. When
mixed with the original sound, an &amp;ldquo;echo&amp;rdquo; is heard. By using &lt;em>feedback&lt;/em> to return
the delayed signal back into the delay (usually after lowering its &lt;em>gain&lt;/em>),
multiple echos with a &lt;em>decay&lt;/em> result.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>&lt;strong>Destructive Editing/Recording&lt;/strong>&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>Destructive actions are those that permanently modify or erase the original
data (sound files) in the course of editing or recording.&lt;/dd>
&lt;/dl>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Distortion&lt;/strong> : Distortion occurs when an audio signal is changed in some way
that produces &lt;em>frequencies&lt;/em> not present in the original. Distortion can be
deliberate or unwanted, and can be produced by driving the signal to a
&lt;em>clipping point&lt;/em>, or by using mathematical transformations to alter the shape (or
&amp;ldquo;waveform&amp;rdquo;) of the signal (usually referred to as &amp;ldquo;waveshaping&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Credits</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/appendices/credits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/appendices/credits/</guid><description>&lt;p>The main body of the manual was written during a &lt;strong>Book Sprint&lt;/strong> led by Derek
Holzer in the &lt;a href="http://moddr.net" title="moddr_lab @ WORM, Rotterdam">moddr_lab&lt;/a> at
WORM in Rotterdam, the Netherlands, between 23 and 27 November 2009, with input
and support from the international community of Ardour users and developers.
The tutorial was originally written for Ardour 2.X versions. The original FLOSS
manual can be found at
&lt;a href="http://archive.flossmanuals.net/ardour/index.html">flossmanuals.net&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Original contributors: Adam Hyde, Bruno Ruviaro, Dave Peticolas, Walter
Langelaar, David Elwell, Thomas Goose, Derick H., Rob Fell, William Abernathy,
Derek Holzer, Stefan Hanser, Tomasz Kaye, Dick MacInnis, Mr Stock, Ross Johnson,
Jon Cohrs, Claudia Borges, Ma Rk, Al Thompson, Jay Maechtlen, Christopher
Stamper, Thomas Margolf, Mark Lindhout, Joern Nettingsmeier.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>License</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/appendices/license/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/appendices/license/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="license">License&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>All chapters copyright of the authors (see below). Unless otherwise
stated all chapters in this manual licensed with &lt;strong>GNU General Public
License version 2&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This documentation is free documentation; you can redistribute it and/or
modify it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published
by the Free Software Foundation; either version 2 of the License, or (at
your option) any later version.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This documentation is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. See the GNU General
Public License for more details.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to contribute</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/appendices/how-to-contribute/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/appendices/how-to-contribute/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-kind-of-contributions-we-accept">What Kind Of Contributions We Accept&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We intentionally limit the scope of this tutorial to very basic techniques that
are sufficient to get users started with recording, mixing, and exporting with
Ardour. So we&amp;rsquo;ll gratefully accept patches that do not change the scope in any
major way: bug fixes, better explanations, better illustrations etc. We also
encourage translations of the ardour-tutorial.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="using-markdown-syntax-and-extras">Using Markdown Syntax And Extras&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>All text files use Markdown syntax with a few extras. We use a limited subset of
available options and one shortcode specific to HTML5, a &lt;code>&amp;lt;figure&amp;gt;&lt;/code> element
(&lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/content-management/shortcodes/#figure">see here&lt;/a> for more
info). Another extra feature available in the template of choice is a so called
shortcode for notice boxes that look like this:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Recommended plugins</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/appendices/plugins/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/appendices/plugins/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="filters-and-processing">Filters and processing&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://lsp-plug.in/">LSP plugins&lt;/a>, an extensive set of plugins for effects and channel processing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://x42-plugins.com/x42/x42-limiter">dpl.lv2&lt;/a>, a look-ahead digital peak limiter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://x42-plugins.com/x42/x42-eq">fil4.lv2&lt;/a>, a 4 band parametric equalizer with additional low &amp;amp; high shelfing and high &amp;amp; low-pass filters&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;h2 id="visualization">Visualization&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://x42-plugins.com/x42/x42-meters">x42 Meter Collection&lt;/a>, a big help in analyzing audio&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://x42-plugins.com/x42/x42-scope">sisco.lv2&lt;/a>, an oscilloscope&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://x42-plugins.com/x42/x42-spectra">spectra.lv2&lt;/a>, a spectrum analyzer&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="drums-and-percussion">Drums and percussion&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://x42-plugins.com/x42/x42-avldrums">AVL Drumkits&lt;/a>, a drum sampler with two built-in kits&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://drumgizmo.org">DrumGizmo&lt;/a>, a drum sampler with separately downloadable kits&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/free-sm/geonkick">Geonkick&lt;/a>, a drums/percussion synthesizer&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="synthesizers">Synthesizers&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/DISTRHO/Cardinal">Cardinal&lt;/a>, a modular synthesizer with Eurorack aesthetics&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/reales/OB-Xd">OB-Xd&lt;/a>, a soft synth resembling vintage Oberheim OB-X synth&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/asb2m10/dexed">Dexed&lt;/a>, a Yamaha DX7 simulator&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.thewavewarden.com/odin2">Odin2&lt;/a>, a 24-voice polyphonic synth&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://surge-synthesizer.github.io/">Surge XT&lt;/a>, a hybrid synthesizer&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://vital.audio/">Vital&lt;/a>, a spectral warping wavetable synth&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://linuxsynths.com/">This website&lt;/a> keeps a track of all software
synthesizers available for Linux.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>