<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Appendices on Ardour tutorial</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/en/appendices/</link><description>Recent content in Appendices on Ardour tutorial</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://prokoudine.github.io/en/appendices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Further help</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/en/appendices/further-help/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/en/appendices/further-help/</guid><description>Besides the URLs listed in the Links chapter, there are a couple of resources on the Internet to help you learn Ardour and fix some of the problems that you might have along the way.
Ardour Manual The official Ardour Manual is the main reference to Ardour. It is a work in progress, meaning you will not find every single feature explained there (yet). But it is already an amazing resource:</description></item><item><title>Glossary</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/en/appendices/glossary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/en/appendices/glossary/</guid><description>This glossary offers brief definitions for many or the terms used throuhout the Ardour3 FLOSS Tutorial.
Aggregate Device (Mac OS X) An Aggregate Device is one virtual soundcard made of of two or more physical soundcards. PowerBooks and MacBooks made in 2007 or later will need this set up in order for JACK to have both input and output channels. This is set up in the Audio MIDI Setup application.</description></item><item><title>Links</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/en/appendices/links/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/en/appendices/links/</guid><description>Useful links:
Ardour: http://ardour.org/
Ardour reference manual (in progress): http://manual.ardour.org/
Jack Audio Connection Kit http://jackaudio.org/
Jack OS X http://jackosx.com/
JAMin http://jamin.sourceforge.net/
Tutorial: Mastering with JAMin and Ardour http://jamin.sourceforge.net/en/tutorial.html
Appendices: FURTHER HELP || GLOSSARY || CREDITS</description></item><item><title>Credits</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/en/appendices/credits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/en/appendices/credits/</guid><description>The main body of the manual was written during a Book Sprint led by Derek Holzer in the moddr_lab at WORM in Rotterdam, the Netherlands, between 23 and 27 November 2009, with input and support from the international community of Ardour users and developers. The tutorial was originally written for Ardour 2.X versions. The original FLOSS manual can be found at flossmanuals.net.
Original contributors: Adam Hyde, Bruno Ruviaro, Dave Peticolas, Walter Langelaar, David Elwell, Thomas Goose, Derick H.</description></item><item><title>License</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/en/appendices/license/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/en/appendices/license/</guid><description>License All chapters copyright of the authors (see below). Unless otherwise stated all chapters in this manual licensed with GNU General Public License version 2.
This documentation is free documentation; you can redistribute it and/or modify it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either version 2 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.
This documentation is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.</description></item></channel></rss>