<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Overview of the Interface on Ardour tutorial</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/overview-of-the-interface/</link><description>Recent content in Overview of the Interface on Ardour tutorial</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/overview-of-the-interface/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Editor window</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/overview-of-the-interface/editor-window/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/overview-of-the-interface/editor-window/</guid><description>When you create a new session, Ardour opens an empty new window called the Editor Window. The Editor Window is the most important window in Ardour, as this is how you will control the program as well as see and edit the audio you have recorded or imported.
At the top of the Editor Window are several main areas: the Transport Menu, the Clocks, the Edit Modes/Cursor Modes menu, the Snap Mode menu and the Auxiliary Controls.</description></item><item><title>Mixer window</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/overview-of-the-interface/mixer-window/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/overview-of-the-interface/mixer-window/</guid><description>Mixer Window Controls The second window, the Mixer Window, can be viewed by going to the main menu and clicking Window &amp;gt; Mixer.
The main function of the Mixer Window is to display all the Mixer Strips for the various Tracks side by side for easy reference. This window is mainly used during the Mixing process, and it also provides access Plugins and other Routing features. See the chapters on Understanding Routing, Mixing and Using Plugins for details.</description></item><item><title>Recorder window</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/overview-of-the-interface/recorder-window/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/overview-of-the-interface/recorder-window/</guid><description>The Recorder window is streamlined for one particular use case: recording to multiple tracks. The interface is pointedly simplified to remove all distraction.
There are three major sections in the Recorder window as outlined above:
Window-specific toolbar The timeline and the tracks representation Inputs control Window-specific toolbar The toolbar has specific commands and information: arming and disarming all tracks for recording, discarding the last take, automatically switching all inputs for signal monitoring, estimation of the time you can record to the disk until it&amp;rsquo;s out of free space etc.</description></item><item><title>Cue window</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/overview-of-the-interface/cue-window/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/overview-of-the-interface/cue-window/</guid><description>TODO
Continuing Now that you are familiar with main Ardour&amp;rsquo;s windows, let&amp;rsquo;s jump to the next section where we create a new track and then import some audio file.
Next: Creating tracks and busses</description></item></channel></rss>