<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Overview of the Interface on Ardour tutorial</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/overview-of-the-interface/</link><description>Recent content in Overview of the Interface on Ardour tutorial</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/overview-of-the-interface/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Editor window</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/overview-of-the-interface/editor-window/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/overview-of-the-interface/editor-window/</guid><description>When you create a new session, Ardour opens an empty new window called the Editor window. The Editor window is the most important window in Ardour, as this is where you arrange track, import and edit media on the timeline, and control plugin automation for creative effects and mixing.
Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at main parts of the Editor window:
Here they are:
Editor-specific toolbar Timeline Tracks and busses Project overview Editor mixer strip Regions, Tracks/Busses, Snapshots, Groups, Ranges, Marks Let&amp;rsquo;s overview them quickly.</description></item><item><title>Mixer window</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/overview-of-the-interface/mixer-window/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/overview-of-the-interface/mixer-window/</guid><description>The Mixer window, can be viewed by going to the main menu and clicking Window &amp;gt; Mixer &amp;gt; Show Mixer. Alternatively, you can press Alt+M.
TODO: not just display mixer strips, but control gain and plugins etc.
The main function of the Mixer window is to display all the mixer strips for the various tracks and busses side by side for easy reference. This window is mainly used during the mixing process.</description></item><item><title>Recorder window</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/overview-of-the-interface/recorder-window/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/overview-of-the-interface/recorder-window/</guid><description>The Recorder window is streamlined for one particular use case: recording to multiple tracks. The interface is pointedly simplified to remove all distraction.
There are three major sections in the Recorder window as outlined above:
Window-specific toolbar The timeline and the tracks representation Inputs control Window-specific toolbar The toolbar has specific commands and information: arming and disarming all tracks for recording, discarding the last take, automatically switching all inputs for signal monitoring, estimation of the time you can record to the disk until it&amp;rsquo;s out of free space etc.</description></item><item><title>Cue window</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/overview-of-the-interface/cue-window/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/overview-of-the-interface/cue-window/</guid><description>The Cue window provides tools to set up live performance using Ardour. We are not going to use Cue in this tutorial, so this is just a quick overview to give you a basic idea what all this is about.
User interface elements The user interface is pretty much standard for this type of a feature set.
Here are the main UI parts:
A grid of clip launchers A browser for reusable clips Clip settings From left to right you get tracks that contain clips (not visible on the timeline when you switch to the Editor window).</description></item></channel></rss>