<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Getting started on Ardour tutorial</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/</link><description>Recent content in Getting started on Ardour tutorial</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Overview of the Interface</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/overview-of-the-interface/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/overview-of-the-interface/</guid><description>This section will give you a basic overview of Ardour&amp;rsquo;s user interface.
We will take a look at shared elements of the interface, main windows, and focus on the Editor window and the Mixer window. Later chapters will give more detailed information on each feature listed here.
Ardour&amp;rsquo;s window Here is a typical view of a project opened in Ardour:
There are two larger parts of the user interface:
Static part that contains program&amp;rsquo;s menu, transport panel, clocks, navigation timeline, and various controls.</description></item><item><title>Starting Ardour</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/starting-ardour/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/starting-ardour/</guid><description>Ardour supports both Linux, Windows, and macOS. There is very little difference about how it works on all these operating systems. So while this tutorial assumes using Ubuntu Linux, you should expect it to work the same way on other operating systems and Linux flavors.
First-launch wizard When you first start Ardour, it will ask you a few questions to make a basic customization: user interface and font scale (if you have a HiDPI display), default folder where new sessions would be created, preferred way to monitor signal being recorded etc.</description></item><item><title>Creating tracks and busses</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/creating-tracks-and-busses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/creating-tracks-and-busses/</guid><description>What are tracks? A track typically represents a part played with one instrument or sung with voice. That part can start in the very beginning and finish at the very end of a song. Or there can be multiple occurences of that instrument/voice within a song, in which case there will likely be multiple regions, or clips, inside a track.
A region is just a portion of audio or MIDI data.</description></item><item><title>Importing audio</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/importing-audio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/importing-audio/</guid><description>Sections of audio are known as regions in Ardour. A Region can be an entire sound file or a portion of it. Here you will learn how to import audio files from the hard drive of your computer so they can be used in your Ardour session.
To import an audio file into your session, you will use the Add Existing Media dialog. Use the shortcut Ctrl+I to get to this window, or alternatively go to the Session &amp;gt; Import menu).</description></item><item><title>Setting up the timeline</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/setting-up-the-timeline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/setting-up-the-timeline/</guid><description>Once you import some audio files to Ardour, play them back and start familiarizing yourself with the user interface, you might want finetuning various parts of the user interface for your needs. The timeline settings are one of the obvious options there, because what you want to see on the timeline largely depends on the kind of material you work on.
Users creating audio plays, documentaries, reportages or soundscapes may wish to use minutes and seconds for units, while those recording bands or producing electronic music will most likely use bars and beats.</description></item><item><title>Installing plugins</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/installing-plugins/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/installing-plugins/</guid><description>While Ardour already ships with some plugins, chances are that you will need more than that: a more sophisticated compressor or reverb, a sampler that can play a high-quality orchestra library, a polyphonic synthesizer etc.
Ardour supports mutiple plugins APIs:
Linux: LADSPA, LV2, VST2.x, VST3 Windows: LADSPA, LV2, VST2.x, VST3 macOS: LADSPA, LV2, VST2.x, VST3, AU You can find a list of recommended free/libre plugins in the appendix.
Installing plugins LADSPA and LV2 These plugins mostly don&amp;rsquo;t have binary builds for Windows and macOS, so on those systems, most of the time you will be dealing with VST2, VST3, or AU.</description></item></channel></rss>