<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Getting started on Ardour tutorial</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/</link><description>Recent content in Getting started on Ardour tutorial</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Overview of the Interface</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/overview-of-the-interface/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/overview-of-the-interface/</guid><description>&lt;p>This section will give you a basic overview of Ardour&amp;rsquo;s user interface.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We will take a look at shared elements of the interface, main windows, and focus
on the &lt;em>Editor&lt;/em> window and the &lt;em>Mixer&lt;/em> window. Later chapters will give more
detailed information on each feature listed here.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ardours-window">Ardour&amp;rsquo;s window&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Here is a typical view of a project opened in Ardour:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="Main window of Ardour 7" src="https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/overview-of-the-interface/en/ardour7-main-window-parts.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are two larger parts of the user interface:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Starting Ardour</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/starting-ardour/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/starting-ardour/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ardour supports both Linux, Windows, and macOS. There is very little
difference about how it works on all these operating systems. So while this
tutorial assumes using Ubuntu Linux, you should expect it to work the same
way on other operating systems and Linux flavors.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="first-launch-wizard">First-launch wizard&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When you first start Ardour, it will ask you a few questions to make a
basic customization: user interface and font scale (if you have a HiDPI
display), default folder where new sessions would be created, preferred way
to monitor signal being recorded etc.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Creating tracks and busses</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/creating-tracks-and-busses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/creating-tracks-and-busses/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-are-tracks">What are tracks?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A track typically represents a part played with one instrument or sung with
voice. That part can start in the very beginning and finish at the very end of
a song. Or there can be multiple occurences of that instrument/voice within a
song, in which case there will likely be multiple &lt;em>regions&lt;/em>, or &lt;em>clips&lt;/em>,
inside a track.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A region is just a portion of audio or MIDI data. For example, a &amp;lsquo;Lead guitar&amp;rsquo;
track can have several regions, one per each solo. Meanwhile, a &amp;lsquo;Drums&amp;rsquo; track
could be just one huge MIDI region spanning the entire song.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Importing audio and MIDI</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/importing-audio-and-midi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/importing-audio-and-midi/</guid><description>&lt;p>You can reuse existing audio and MIDI files by adding them as regions on
existing or new tracks. To do so, press the &lt;strong>Ctrl+I&lt;/strong> shortcut or go to the
&lt;code>Session &amp;gt; Import&lt;/code> menu to open the &lt;em>Add Existing Media&lt;/em> dialog, pick a file
of interest, and import it.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/importing-audio-and-midi/en/ardour7-import-as-new-tracks.png"
alt="Add Media">
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Some settings are the same for audio and MIDI, some are format-specific.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="playing-existing-files">Playing existing files&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before you import a file, it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to make sure it&amp;rsquo;s the right one. On
the right side of the &lt;em>Add Existing Media&lt;/em> dialog you will see a section
allowing you to inspect the properties of the file you selected. Here you will
see the name, number of channels, sample rate, format and length of the sound
file, along with any tags you have chosen to add to the file.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Setting up the timeline</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/setting-up-the-timeline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/setting-up-the-timeline/</guid><description>&lt;p>Once you import some audio files to Ardour, play them back and start
familiarizing yourself with the user interface, you might want finetuning
various parts of the user interface for your needs. The timeline settings are
one of the obvious options there, because what you want to see on the timeline
largely depends on the kind of material you work on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Users creating audio plays, documentaries, reportages or soundscapes may wish
to use minutes and seconds for units, while those recording bands or producing
electronic music will most likely use bars and beats. Video producers will
find a frames-per-second timecode handy, while those wishing for extreme
precision may even want to use samples. All of these can be viewed in Ardour
and used as a means to organize your regions and edits.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Installing plugins</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/installing-plugins/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/installing-plugins/</guid><description>&lt;p>While Ardour already ships with some plugins, chances are that you will need
more than that: a more sophisticated compressor or reverb, a sampler that
can play a high-quality orchestra library, a polyphonic synthesizer etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ardour supports mutiple plugins APIs:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Linux&lt;/strong>: LADSPA, LV2, VST2.x, VST3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Windows&lt;/strong>: LADSPA, LV2, VST2.x, VST3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>macOS&lt;/strong>: LADSPA, LV2, VST2.x, VST3, AU&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>You can find a list of recommended free/libre plugins
&lt;a href="https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/ardour-tutorial/en/appendices/plugins/">in the appendix&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="installing-plugins">Installing plugins&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="ladspa-and-lv2">LADSPA and LV2&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>These plugins mostly don&amp;rsquo;t have binary builds for Windows and macOS, so on
those systems, most of the time you will be dealing with VST2, VST3, or AU.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>