<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Getting started on Ardour tutorial</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/</link><description>Recent content in Getting started on Ardour tutorial</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Starting JACK</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/starting-jack/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/starting-jack/</guid><description>Originally, JACK audio server was designed to provide a low-latency audio workflow on Linux with complex routing and transport between audio and MIDI applications as well as physical audio interface ports. JACK is available on both Linux, Windows, and macOS.
Today, the use of JACK audio server is discouraged by Ardour developers except for particular use cases like sophisticated signal routing. For simple multichannel recording your user experience will be vastly better when relying on native audio engine available in your operating system, like ALSA on Linux and Core Audio on macOS.</description></item><item><title>Starting Ardour</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/starting-ardour-on-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/starting-ardour-on-ubuntu/</guid><description>Once you have started Ardour, the Session Setup window shows up.
You can click on New Session to create a brand new session, or you can open an existing session using the Other Sessions options. For now let&amp;rsquo;s create a fresh session, so click on New Session. The window should now look like the screenshot below.
Name your new project and click Open .
Avoid using any characters other than letters and numbers when naming your session.</description></item><item><title>Overview of the Interface</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/overview-of-the-interface/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/overview-of-the-interface/</guid><description>This section will give you an overview of the basic interface of Ardour.
We will take a look at the Editor Window and the Mixer Window. Later chapters will give more detailed information on each feature listed here.
The Editor Window When you create a new session, Ardour opens an empty new window called the Editor Window. The Editor Window is the most important window in Ardour, as this is how you will control the program as well as see and edit the audio you have recorded or imported.</description></item></channel></rss>