<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Getting started on Ardour tutorial</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/</link><description>Recent content in Getting started on Ardour tutorial</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Starting Ardour</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/starting-ardour-on-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/starting-ardour-on-ubuntu/</guid><description>Ardour supports both Linux, Windows, and macOS. There is very little difference about how it works on all these operating systems. So while this tutorial assumes using Ubuntu Linux, you should expect it to work the same way on other operating systems and Linux flavors.
First-launch wizard When you first start Ardour, it will ask you a few questions to make a basic customization: user interface and font scale (if you have a HiDPI display), default folder where new sessions would be created, preferred way to monitor signal being recorded etc.</description></item><item><title>Creating tracks and busses</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/creating-tracks-and-busses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/creating-tracks-and-busses/</guid><description>What is an Audio Track? An Audio Track is a place where you can drag a Region from your Region List and where you can record sounds coming from an outside source.
A Region represents an audio clip, i.e., one of your sound files or just a portion of a sound file. In the image below, the horizontal strip areas marked &amp;ldquo;MyTrack&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;short-drone-mono&amp;rdquo; are Tracks. The rectangles containing audio information are called Regions (for example, the Region &amp;ldquo;wheels-mono.</description></item><item><title>Importing audio</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/importing-audio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/importing-audio/</guid><description>Sections of audio are known as Regions in Ardour. A Region can be an entire sound file or a portion of it. Here you will learn how to import audio files from the hard drive of your computer so they can be used in your Ardour session.
To import an audio file into your session, you will use the Add existing media dialog. Use the shortcut Ctrl+I to get to this window, or alternatively go to the Session &amp;gt; Import menu).</description></item><item><title>Setting up the timeline</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/setting-up-the-timeline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/getting-started/setting-up-the-timeline/</guid><description>Because different users will want to use Ardour for different tasks, the way time is measured in the application can be changed.
Users creating audio plays, documentaries, reportages or soundscapes may wish to use Minutes and Seconds, for example, while those recording bands or producing electronic music will most likely use Bars and Beats. Video producers will find a frames-per-second Timecode handy, while those wishing for extreme precision may even want to use Samples.</description></item></channel></rss>