<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Starting sessions on Ardour tutorial</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/starting-sessions/</link><description>Recent content in Starting sessions on Ardour tutorial</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/starting-sessions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Starting a session</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/starting-sessions/starting-a-session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/starting-sessions/starting-a-session/</guid><description>Ardour groups your work in Sessions. A Session is a group of Tracks which eventually may be mixed down into a single Mono, Stereo or multi-channel sound file. Sessions are essentially projects; all your data is saved in a single Session folder.
When you start Ardour, you are asked if you want to start a new Session or open an existing one. When creating a new Session you must choose a name for it.</description></item><item><title>Setting up the timeline</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/starting-sessions/setting-up-the-timeline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/starting-sessions/setting-up-the-timeline/</guid><description>Because different users will want to use Ardour for different tasks, the way time is measured in the application can be changed.
Users creating audio plays, documentaries, reportages or soundscapes may wish to use Minutes and Seconds, for example, while those recording bands or producing electronic music will most likely use Bars and Beats. Video producers will find a frames-per-second Timecode handy, while those wishing for extreme precision may even want to use Samples.</description></item><item><title>Creating a track or a bus</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/starting-sessions/creating-a-track-or-bus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/starting-sessions/creating-a-track-or-bus/</guid><description>What is an Audio Track? An Audio Track is a place where you can drag a Region from your Region List and where you can record sounds coming from an outside source.
A Region represents an audio clip, i.e., one of your sound files or just a portion of a sound file. In the image below, the horizontal strip areas marked &amp;ldquo;MyTrack&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;short-drone-mono&amp;rdquo; are Tracks. The rectangles containing audio information are called Regions (for example, the Region &amp;ldquo;wheels-mono.</description></item><item><title>Importing audio</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/starting-sessions/importing-audio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/starting-sessions/importing-audio/</guid><description>Sections of audio are known as Regions in Ardour. A Region can be an entire sound file or a portion of it. Here you will learn how to import audio files from the hard drive of your computer so they can be used in your Ardour session.
To import an audio file into your session, you will use the Add existing media dialog. Use the shortcut Ctrl+I to get to this window, or alternatively go to the Session &amp;gt; Import menu).</description></item><item><title>Recording audio</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/starting-sessions/recording-audio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/starting-sessions/recording-audio/</guid><description>Besides Importing Audio, another way to create Regions in your Ardour session is to record new audio.
The source of this audio could be the line or microphone inputs of your audio interface, or it could even be sound originating from other applications on your computer which have been connected to Ardour via JACK. Please see the section on Routing for more details.
This section will show you how to record audio from an external source (for example, a microphone) onto a track in Ardour.</description></item><item><title>Understanding routing</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/starting-sessions/understanding-routing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/starting-sessions/understanding-routing/</guid><description>Routing an audio signal is sending it from somewhere to somewhere else.
In addition to getting audio signals to and from Ardour, routing plays an important part inside Ardour itself. Examples of using routing inside Ardour include routing audio from Tracks to the Master Bus or to other Busses, creating &amp;lsquo;sends&amp;rsquo;, routing the outputs from Busses to the Master Bus, etc. (see chapter on Creating a Track for an explanation of Tracks and Busses).</description></item><item><title>Routing between applications</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/starting-sessions/routing-between-applications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/starting-sessions/routing-between-applications/</guid><description>Sometimes you may need to record the audio output of another program into Ardour (for example, the sound of a YouTube video playing in Firefox, or the output of SuperCollider or PureData). This chapter shows how to accomplish that.
The examples on this page were created on a computer running Ubuntu Linux. Beware that things may work differently if you are on another OS (in particular if you are using a Mac, in which case you will be using JackPilot).</description></item></channel></rss>