<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Exporting sessions on Ardour tutorial</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/exporting-sessions/</link><description>Recent content in Exporting sessions on Ardour tutorial</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/exporting-sessions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Exporting a session</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/exporting-sessions/exporting-a-session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/exporting-sessions/exporting-a-session/</guid><description>Exporting is the process of saving a region, track, or entire session to a file on your computer which you can listen to, burn as a CD-R, or convert to an MP3 to share on a website.
Export the Entire Session Once you have finished your composition, the most common export operation is to export the entire session to an audio file.
Bird&amp;rsquo;s Eye View of Entire Session At this point it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to zoom out and take a look at your whole session before exporting.</description></item><item><title>Exporting a range</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/exporting-sessions/exporting-a-range/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/exporting-sessions/exporting-a-range/</guid><description>Learn how to export a selected portion (Range) of your Session.
Exporting is the process of saving a Region, Track or Session to a file on your computer. As we learned previously, exporting an isolated Region does not export all of the changes you might have made to that Region. To export edits such as Panning, Fader Automation, and Plugin effects, you must Export either a Range or the entire Session.</description></item><item><title>Exporting regions</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/exporting-sessions/exporting-a-region/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/exporting-sessions/exporting-a-region/</guid><description>You may wish to export only a region of your session, perhaps to use as a sample in another application, or to edit it in a different program. This chapter shows you how to do that.
Exporting a Region To export a region, select it (so it becomes blue), and then right-click into the sub-menu Export, or use the top menu: Region &amp;gt; Export.
This will open up the same export dialog box explained in the Exporting a Session chapter.</description></item></channel></rss>