<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Saving sessions on Ardour tutorial</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/saving-sessions/</link><description>Recent content in Saving sessions on Ardour tutorial</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/saving-sessions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Saving a session</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/saving-sessions/saving-a-session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/saving-sessions/saving-a-session/</guid><description>There are a number of ways to save Sessions in Ardour, so that each session can be use later on. The simplest way is to save the entire session just like you would save other documents: hitting Ctrl+S.
A new session is first saved at the moment you create it. While you are working on it, you should save it frequently. Get into the habit of hitting Ctrl+S (or Command+S on a Mac) every few minutes.</description></item><item><title>Saving a snapshot</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/saving-sessions/saving-a-snapshot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/saving-sessions/saving-a-snapshot/</guid><description>A snapshot is a representation of the current state of a session. In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s like versioning your project by giving every version a meaningful, descriptive name. Even though it&amp;rsquo;s not really exposed to users, every session always has at least one snapshot which is whatever you have there at the moment.
Let&amp;rsquo;s say you recorded a song in your home studio and you are trying different arrangements to see which one works best.</description></item><item><title>Saving a template</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/saving-sessions/saving-a-template/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/saving-sessions/saving-a-template/</guid><description>If you often go through the motions of setting up the same information in each new session you create, such as tracks/busses, their names and interconnections, what plugins with what settings you have in mixer channels etc., then you may wish to create a template instead.
With a template, you can save the state of a currently open session without all the region information files. Templates are useful if, for example, you&amp;rsquo;re doing extensive routing on tracks and busses and want to save the Editor window&amp;rsquo;s state for use in other sessions.</description></item></channel></rss>