<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Saving sessions on Ardour tutorial</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/saving-sessions/</link><description>Recent content in Saving sessions on Ardour tutorial</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/saving-sessions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Saving a session</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/saving-sessions/saving-a-session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/saving-sessions/saving-a-session/</guid><description>There are a number of ways to save Sessions in Ardour, so that each Session can be use later on. The simplest way is to save the entire Session just like you would save other documents: hitting &amp;ldquo;Control&amp;rdquo; + &amp;ldquo;S&amp;rdquo;.
A new Session is first saved at the moment you create it. While you are working on it, you should save it frequently. Get into the habit of hitting &amp;ldquo;Control&amp;rdquo; + &amp;ldquo;S&amp;rdquo; (or &amp;ldquo;Command&amp;rdquo; + &amp;ldquo;S&amp;rdquo; on a Mac) every few minutes.</description></item><item><title>Saving a snapshot</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/saving-sessions/saving-a-snapshot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/saving-sessions/saving-a-snapshot/</guid><description>Saving a Snapshot in Ardour is similar to saving your Session to a new file, however using a Snapshot avoids overwriting the original Session file. A Snapshot contains the current state of your work, while sharing all the audio and data files of the Session.
Saving a Snapshot You can save a Snapshot via the menu: Session &amp;gt; Snapshot (shortcut &amp;ldquo;Control&amp;rdquo; + &amp;ldquo;Shift&amp;rdquo; + &amp;ldquo;S&amp;rdquo;).
By default the program will name the new Snapshot according to the current date and timestamp of your system.</description></item><item><title>Saving a template</title><link>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/saving-sessions/saving-a-template/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prokoudine.github.io/ardour-tutorial/en/saving-sessions/saving-a-template/</guid><description>If you often go through the motions of setting up the same information in each new Session you create, such as the number of input and output Channels, the number and names of Tracks or Busses, or the Routing, then you may wish to create a Template of that information instead.
With a Template, you can save the state of a currently open Session without all the Region information files. Templates are useful if, for example, you&amp;rsquo;re doing extensive Routing on Tracks and Buses and want to save the Editor Window&amp;rsquo;s state for use in other Sessions.</description></item></channel></rss>